[Music]
prudential has now spent five fruitful
years helping zambians get the most out
of life
with a diverse offering of life and
health insurance packages and also an
array of retirement and asset management
solutions
kachizakuenda is prudential's acting
chief executive officer he's part of a
generation of bright adventurous
executives that turn to big ideas when
they mean to solve age-old problems
particularly the never-ending quest for
growth that trickles down to ordinary
zambians with ordinary incomes it's been
an interesting journey over the last
five years from when prudential came up
to where we are today we had to align
our processes with group but also add
our own flair of how we do things what's
very interesting about prudential is
that we run a federated model so what
that means is that even though we're
part of a multinational we still have
leeway to have our nuanced views of what
happens in country so that's been very
very exciting
what's also been great about it is the
chance we've had to get expertise from
around the globe
to be able to be infused in our local
environment but similarly we've been
able to exchange ideas and transfer
knowledge from zambia to the rest of the
world through prudential nobody is
perfect but day by day we make sure
we're better than we were yesterday
beyond that we'd like to make prudential
a place where all our employees enjoy
being here where they can express
themselves and also grow into their
potential prudential plc is essentially
an asia-led portfolio of businesses
focused on structural growth markets a
structural growth market is one that has
unlimited potential for growth in zambia
prudential is a key player in the
fast-growing life assurance industry
with more than 120 000 clients and a
presence in nine of the nation's ten
provinces the company prides itself on
its ability to offer modern high quality
services its determination to help spur
economic growth in zambia and a genuine
compassion for the communities in which
it operates
most zambians will know that prudence
the charming lady in prudential's logo
embodies the company's spirit of
enduring strength wisdom and also its
global outlook so what does team
prudential say exactly when asked what
does prove mean to you what prudential
means to me is empowerment prudential
has opened me to a wide range of
knowledge in the corporate world
prudential for me is a place that
provides opportunity to sharpen my
skills and also it's a fun place to
interact and meet new people from
diverse works of life if all of these
people sound like the exact sort you'd
hang out with after five that's because
prudential recruits them very carefully
prudential the way chief operations
officer raymond gomer puts it takes
people very seriously the success that
prudential has enjoyed during the last
five years can largely be attributed to
our dedicated workforce that we've built
over the period of five years now
we have doubled our health count to
ensure that we keep responding to the
demanding needs of our customers and
ensure that we are responsive and
providing solutions that meet the needs
and wants of our customers
our staff have been a key pillar in this
journey simply because
we do understand their needs and their
wants
and over and above that we've
developed our staff the last five years
to ensure that we equip them with the
necessary skills and knowledge around
the trends in meeting the needs and
wants of our customers if you don't
believe raymond you can always ask the
people themselves
as in just how much prudential is done
in just five years
prudential has grown its corporate
business departments
we've seen some phenomenal growth in the
corporate business space
all coming from the partnerships we are
having from
the brokers the agents and of course our
valued customers
we have seen ourselves growing by at
least 30 percent each year in each of
the lines of business
when we started we were number four in
the market and now we are number two
number one is all that's coming and i'm
sure watch this space we should be
number one very soon prudential has paid
out a wealth of claims without a
moment's hesitation prudential prides
itself and bring an efficient pair of
claims
in the last five years we've paid over
6.8 million u.s dollars in maturities as
liquid intelligence technology
we have chosen prudential as a medical
insurance provider of choice why because
number one it's their responsiveness the
experience that we get from prudential
number two it's because of the
the where prudential has come to our
head especially in time in times of
needs
we've had some serious medical complex
related issues
they've come to our head and they've
helped us to focus on what we do best i
used to have pain on my left arm
for quite some time almost five years
and i used to go to italian hospital
always for this year and so
but then later on they did the scan
and they discovered that i
had had
spondolosis
so the only way out was to carry out an
operation
which was almost five hours operation
but then
it was on the higher side
so since i'm with prudential i could
they called prudential find out if they
could carry out that operation
which only took five minutes
and the answer was given to say go ahead
carry out that operation which they did
they had to open my throats here
did whatever they had to do the doctors
i'd love to thank prudential insurance
because you know with other insurance
companies it would take almost four or
five days for them to approve but in
their case it only took less than five
minutes
they gave a go ahead to say you see we
are here to save people's lives minus
prudential i think by now could have
been six feet prudential has helped
countless sales agents turn opportunity
into responsibility
our number of agents
has grown from 300 to over 2 300.
our revenue has tripled
one good story that comes to mind is the
growth in the hni
segment
where we had to start with three
consultants
and grow that number over time today i
am proud to mention
that that channel
is now 36 percent of our agent's
business we have provided our clients
with covenant in cover we've also
extended this cover to our members of
staff
and our hard-working consultants like
many people i had a misconception about
sales jobs of course that conception
quickly changed as soon as i joined
prudential i have worked with prudential
life assurance for four years now and
like every business and job it's had its
own hurdles and rewards for me being a
sales consultant goes beyond selling
it's the whole customer experience
challenge that's very exciting from
building the relationship offering the
service and of course ensuring customer
satisfaction
prudential has created real and lasting
value for zambians prudential's
differentiated agency model supports
small business owners to set up scale
and succeed at their businesses in
helping people get the most out of life
prudential not only provides seed
capital but also cutting edge technology
and training as well as marketing
support and brand building to help these
small business owners grow into middle
and large enterprises with prudential
prudential has given back to the
community we've been able to make an
impact in the communities that we
operate in through our safe steps road
safety campaign we've been able to save
zambian lives by educating them on how
to safely use the roads
we've also taken up initiatives where we
educate children on financial literacy
through our teaching program under the
pillars of education financial literacy
and health and wellness we have been
able to make an impact in the lives of
many zambians
prudential in short is helping people
get the most out of life what helping
people get the most out of life means to
me
as an information analyst is
providing analysis
that is diagnostic
prescriptive
and predictive in nature
thus helping both my external
and internal clients to make
well-informed decisions we are excited
about the future as we have lots of
opportunities ahead of us as we continue
to increase the insurance uptake in the
industry
we are equally excited because we have
observed growing demand for health
savings and protection solutions from
our customers which actually gives us an
opportunity for us to deliver on our
promise
and our commitment to our customers
remains that we continue to deliver
excellence and in achieving that what
we're planning to do and we'll continue
to work on is a digital roadmap that
will ensure that we deliver and save our
customers with speed as well as expand
our reach
[Music]
here's to the next five years of helping
people get the most out of life
[Music]
you